Subindex build by Linnet
http://linnet.126.com  http://blog.csdn.net/redbirdli
火鸟字幕合并器SubindexV0.5
Created time 09.11.25 19:28:29
-=THE LAST FANTASY=- 荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=- 翻译：psjmz 校对：ch1plus1
Attention, Mr. Hayes, your wife is waiting at the station.
Oh, it was after-- You know, after last year's corporate...
自去年后进入公司后
...my wife was always encouraging me, you know?
我的妻子就一直鼓励我
She said, "No, you did fine in the corporate." I was a bit nervous.
她说，你干得很出色 我有些紧张
This little guy. Hello? Sorry.
这小麦克风…哈罗，对不起
-That's nice, eh? -Yeah.
-这样很好，是吗？ -是的
Nice background with the people.
很好的背景，有人在那里
-We are here at-- Must I look in there? -Look into the lens.
- 我们现在在...我必须这样看？ - 直视镜头即可
We are here at MNU head office, Department of Alien Affairs.
我们现在在MNU（多国联）总部 外星人事务部
My name is Wikus van de Merwe.
我是维库斯·范德默尔
And behind me you can see other Alien Affairs workers.
在我身后，你可以看到 外星人事务部的其它工作人员
And what we do here at this department is...
我们这个部门的工作是
...we try to engage with the prawn on behalf of MNU...
试图与大虾沟通
...and on behalf of humans.
为了MNU和人类的利益
To everyone's surprise, the ship didn't come to a stop...
让所有人都感到意外的是 太空船并没有停在
...over Manhattan or Washington or Chicago...
曼哈顿，华盛顿，抑或芝加哥
...but instead coasted to a halt directly over the city of Johannesburg.
而是直接停在了约翰内斯堡上空
The doors didn't open for months. Nobody could get in.
船门在三个月内都没有打开 它就悬浮在那里，没人能够进去
They eventually decided, after much deliberation, that the best thing to do...
在深思熟虑之后，他们终于决定
...would be to physically cut their way in.
最好的方法是切割飞船破门而入
We're gonna need a drill down here.
我们得在这里钻个孔
ye were on the verge of first contact.
我们即将进行第一次接触
The whole world was watching.
整个世界的目光都聚集于此
We need some more light.
我们需要更多的光线
Expecting, I don't know, music from heaven and bright shining lights.
期待，还是别的，我也不清楚 或许是音乐伴着强光闪耀从天而降
Got a lot of moisture in here.
发现有大量的水
Yeah, just go slowly.
是吗，慢步向前
Oh, my God.
哦，天呀
The creatures were extremely malnourished.
这些生物非常营养不良
They were very unhealthy. They seemed to be aimless.
他们非常不健康，看起来精神恍惚
There was a lot of international pressure on us at the time.
当时我们顶着来自世界各地的压力
The world was looking at Johannesburg...
整个世界都在盯着约翰内斯堡
...so we had to do the right thing.
因此，我们必须把事情处理好
The government then established an aid group...
随后政府成立了一个援救小组
...that started to ferry the aliens to a temporary camp that was set up...
开始将这些外星人运送到船下方
...just beneath the ship.
临时建立营地里
ye didn't have a plan.
我们事先并没有明确的计划
There was a million of them.
他们有数百万
So, what was a temporary holding zone...
因此，临时的收容所很快就加上了围篱
...soon became fenced, became militarized.
成为了隔离区并开始实施军事化管理
And before we knew it, it was a slum.
而在我们知道之前，这是一个贫民窟
Well, the truth is nobody really knew what this place was.
但事实是，没人真正知道 这究竟是什么地方
There's a lot of secrets in District 9.
在第九区有很多不为人知的秘密
片名：第九区
At first, a lot of attention was given to giving the aliens...
起初，大家比较关注
...proper status and protection.
如何给予外星人一个适当的身份和保护
They're spending so much money to keep them here...
为了维持那些外星人生存 政府花费了大量的金钱
...when they could be spending it on other things. But at least--
这些钱本该用在其它地方的，但至少
At least they're keeping them separate from us.
但至少这把外星人和我们隔离开了
（非人类勿进）
（非人类勿在此地逗留）
I wanna be realistic with everyone.
我希望每个人都应该实际点
-The aliens will not be able to go home. -The aliens are here to stay.
-这些外星人不可能回到他们原来的星球了 -外星人会在这里长留下来
There were literally thousands of theories as to why...
对于船无法操作这件事
...the ship seemed inoperable.
人们众说纷纭
And what was speculated was that a command module had detached itself...
其中有种推测是
...from the main ship and then somehow mysteriously become lost.
指挥舱已经和主船分离了 然后，又莫名其妙地失踪了
Did it fall by itself or was it programmed?
它是自己掉下来的还是按照预定程序掉落的？
I don't know.
我也不知道
Examination of the old video footage...
认真检查这些旧的影像镜头
...shows very clearly that a piece falls from the ship.
可以清楚地发现有一小块东西 从船上掉落下来
We looked everywhere. There's pieces falling off that vessel for months.
我们到处搜索它 几个月里有很多东西从主船上落下来
More energy weapon caches found.
我们发现了很多藏匿的武器
The special task force conducted raids in District 9....
特种部队突袭了第九区
Where there's a weapon, there's crime. Tensions rose and rose.
有武器的地方就有犯罪 气氛变得越来越紧张
People became more and more fed up, and eventually the rioting started.
人们变得越来越愤怒并最终引发了骚乱
Residents in Tembisa rioted for the third consecutive night...
塔比萨的居民连续暴动了三个晚上
...in an attempt to remove all the aliens from their township.
目地是为了把外星人从他们的城区驱赶走
I think they must fix that ship and they must go.
我认为他们一定要修好那艘船 他们必须离开
A virus, a selective virus.
病毒，精心挑选一种病毒、
Release it near the aliens.
把它释放到外星人附近
They must just go. I don't know where, but they must just go!
他们必须滚蛋 不管滚哪，尽管滚开
If they were from another country, we might understand...
如果他们是来自其它国家的话也就算了
...but they are not even from this planet at all.
但他们甚至都不是地球上的
The government have enforced a nationwide curfew.
政府已下令实施全国宵禁
These aliens-- Prawns. --they take my wife away.
那些外星人，那些大虾 他们夺走了我的妻子
The derogatory term "prawn" is used.
这个贬损的词“大虾”用来指那些外星人
Obviously, it implies something that is a bottom feeder...
很明显，它暗指那些以食腐为生的
...that scavenges the leftovers.
低等动物
You can't say they don't look like that. They look like prawns.
我的意思是，你总不能说他们不像吧 他们看起来就像只虾
Aliens made off with an undisclosed amount of cash.
外星人抢走了数额不明的现金
One bystander was hurt.
一个围观者受伤了
What for an alien might be seen as something recreational...
在外星人看来很娱乐的事情
...setting fire to a truck, derailing a train...
比如放火点燃汽车，让火车出轨
...is for us, obviously, an extremely destructive act.
对我们而言，这些可都是相当极端的破坏行为
They can take the sneakers you are wearing off you.
他们会抢走你穿的运动鞋
They check the brand and take them. They take whatever you have on you.
他们会抢走你身上的一切
Your cell phone or anything.
你的手机或者其它任何东西
After that, they kill you.
之后，他们会杀了你
After 20 years, public pressure forced the government...
20年后的今天，来自公众的压力迫使政府
...to ship the aliens out of Johannesburg.
将这些外星人运出约翰内斯堡
They had had enough, and they wanted District 9 to be moved...
他们受够了，他们要把第九区搬走
...and more intensively policed and controlled.
并受到更多警力更强的控制
To enforce eviction, the government turned to Multi-National United.
为了实施这个大型的驱逐行动 政府借助于MNU的力量
Welcome all, and thank you for coming.
欢迎你们，谢谢你们的到来
Please listen very closely to this briefing.
请仔细听这个简短的指示
Today we start a very complex and delicate operation.
今天我们要开始一个非常复杂和棘手的任务
This is the Iargest operation that MNU has ever undertaken...
这是MNU所执行过的最大的任务
...and we believe that it is going to be undertaken successfully.
我们坚信这个任务一定会执行地非常成功
It is to move 1.8 million prawns...
这次我们要将180万大虾
...from their present home in District 9 to a safer and better location...
从他们现有的家第九区转移到 离约翰内斯堡200公里之外的
...200 kilometers outside of Johannesburg city.
一个更好和更安全的场所
ye've built a nice, new facility where the prawn can go.
我们在那里为他们建造了一个更舒适的新环境
He can be comfortable. He can stay there.
大虾能够过得相对舒适 它们可以呆在那里
The people of Johannesburg and of South Africa are going to live...
远离大虾的骚扰后，约翰内斯堡和南非的居民
...happily and safely, knowing that that prawn is very far away.
就可以过上快乐又安全的生活
UIO protocol dictates that we give the aliens 24-hours' notice...
UIO协议规定我们至少要在驱逐前24小时
...of our right to evict.
给予外星人的驱逐通知
Today, you will serve these notices...
今天，你们的任务就是宣布这一正式通知
...getting the aliens to sign the I-27 form.
并让外星人们签订I-27协议
The legality that MNU is using to evict the aliens is simply a whitewash.
MNU用来驱逐外星人的法律 实际上只是一个幌子
So I'm going to appoint a field officer to take direct command.
我将任命一个现场指挥官来直接指挥这次任务
Wikus van de Merwe.
维库斯·范德默尔
Everybody always said that Wikus was not a very smart boy...
大家都认为维库斯不是一个非常机灵的孩子
...but he was a wonderful son.
但他是一个很好的儿子
That was my Wikus. Just--
那就是我的维库斯，正如…
Yes. Like up on the big stage. Thank you, Piet. Mr. Smit.
感觉人生又向前迈了一大步 谢谢你，皮耶特·史密斯先生
I had to put aside the fact that my daughter was married to yikus.
我得抛开我女儿嫁给维库斯这个事实
That didn't factor in my decision.
这点并没有影响我是否提升他
It's almost as big as my wedding day. You know, not as big.
这个升职几乎和我结婚的日子一样重大 嗯...当然还没有结婚那么重大
Wikus was always making me things.
维库斯总给我亲手制作很多东西
He said that way, they just mean so much more.
他说这这些东西都情深意长
He left this papier-m芒ch茅 ball on the sofa one day...
有一次，他把这个纸碗放在了沙发上
...and I didn't see it and I sat down and I--
而我并没有看到，坐下去了
I kind of squished it.
差点把它坐扁了
They took all his stuff away for the investigation...
他们把他的所有东西都带去调查了
...and I made them bring it all back.
而我向他们把东西全都要回来了
-Congratulations, man. -Oh, thanks, man.
-恭喜你，年轻人 -谢谢，先生
-Okay, you're gonna go to P-7. -Wikus. Wikus.
-好，你去P7 -维库斯，维库斯
Leslie. How's it going, man? There's the shake. P-9 for you.
莱斯利，事情怎样了？ 这么办吧，P9归你
I'm not saying what he did was right.
我并不是说他做的都是对的
He took the choices that were given.
他只能那样做了
This is Trent. Fundiswa, Trent. Trent, Fundiswa.
这是特伦特，方德斯瓦，特伦特
-Hi. -Fundiswa's the guy I've selected...
-你好 -方德斯瓦是我挑选来
...to replace me. If he can make it today, eh?
替补我的人 今天他能行吗？
-I'll make it. -You think you can?
-我行啦 -你认为你行？
I just want everyone watching this...
我现在只想每个能看到这个的观众
...to learn from what has happened.
都能从中学到一些东西
You would think things like this happen to somebody else, not me.
你可能会认为这些事情只会发生在别人身上 而不会发生在自己身上
Guys, don't forget to pack the stun grenades.
弟兄们，不要忘记了带好手榴弹
Tovi. There's Tovi. How's it going, man? A long time, eh?
托维，这是托维 怎样，好久不见了？
-You got my stuff? -Hey, big boss.
-有我的东西吧？ -嘿，头
-How's it going? -I'm all right.
-最近怎样了？ -很好
This is Fundiswa. He's training with us today.
好，好，这是方德斯瓦 他今天和我们一起训练
I think I was-- "Disgusted" would be the word.
我认为“令人厌烦的”是个最好的词
There was always a hint of something not kosher with van de Merwe.
我一直觉得范德默尔有点不太对劲
Nobody saw it coming. None of us had any idea of what he was doing.
没人能够意料到 没人知道下一步他会干啥
I think it's a great thing that it's not the military guys in charge this time.
这次由非军方人员统领是一件好事情
Not to say Koobus and the cowboys are not wanted. You're always wanted.
当然，并不是说库布斯和他那些牛仔们不再重要了 你们这些家伙一直很重要
You see now? These are the cowboys.
你也看到了吧？ 这些都是他的牛仔
-Get out! -Fire!
-闪开！ -开火！
They shoot first and then answer the questions.
他们先训练，然后才接受采访
You can see-- Hey, sorry, sorry.
你可以看到… 嘿，打扰一下，打扰一下
That's above the allocated amount of ammunition.
这些弹药是不是超量了
Your pouches are full, but you still carry.
你装了满满一袋子了，你却还在拿
Maybe you should speak to the colonel.
也许你应该直接跟上校谈谈
I just think that you should--
我只是觉得你应该…
FNG over here says that we got too much ammunition.
F.A.G过来说我们带太多弹药了
All I'm saying, Koobus, is that, you know, you should find ways...
不，我的意思是，库布斯，是那个
...of making your guys more efficient, you know?
你应该提高他们的工作效率
Listen to me, you fuck! Get that fucking camera out of my face.
听着，你他妈的混小子！ 赶紧让他滚远点
Fucking doos.
死傻B
There are rules. We're all living by rules.
无规矩不成方圆， 我们都按照规矩行事
I don't think he can be forgiven. It was like a betrayal.
我认为他那种行为是不可原谅的 这和背叛无异
I've gotta get going, guys. I think we're gonna have to cut this. We're gonna go.
我们得开始出发了，伙计们 我想我们应该剪掉这个，准备出发
This is tangled. This is tangled.
这真纠结，这真纠结
-Move it, move it. -Come on, let's go.
-走，走 -走，我们走
-Hurry up. Go on. Go on. -Go, go, go.
-快走，快，快 -走，走，走
ye've got four teams in the air and three teams on the ground.
你有四支空中小组 和三支地面小组
第九区12公里外
Got a visual on the ground crew. We can take it into position.
已发现地面小组，本组即将就位
Copy that.
收到
These are full. Check your magazines, people. Come on. Let's go.
这些都是满的，拿好你的弹药 伙计们，我们出发了
The prawn doesn't really understand the concept of ownership of property.
大虾并没有产权的概念
So we have to come there and say, "Listen, this is our land.
因此，我们去到那里跟他们说： 听着，这是我们的土地
Please will you go?"
拜托，你们能不能离开？
It's difficult to put the vest on by yourself.
光靠自己很难穿上防弹背心
-Thomas, can you help me? -They told me I was going to get a vest.
-托马斯，你能帮帮我吗？ -他们说我也要穿防弹背心
Just look-- Thomas, just look on the side if there's a vest there.
看那，托马斯 那边是不是有件防弹背心
-I'm concerned about my family. -Look, don't worry. It'll be fine.
-我只是担心我的家人 -别担心，一切都会很顺利的
Rights groups have demanded that mercenaries...
人权组织已经要求雇佣兵们
...should comply with all UIO regulations in District 9.
在第九区应该遵从UIO规则
ye're coming to you from the entrance of District 9...
我们在第九区的入口出为你报道
...as today Multi-National United sets out to relocate...
今天，MNU将开始重新安置
...approximately 1 .8 million alien residents from their homes.
大约180万名外星居民
Human-rights groups are keeping a watchful eye, as many suspect...
人权组织正在保持密切关注
...abuses might occur.
因为可能会发生不少虐待外星人的行为
We're seeing heavily armed private security forces...
我们正看到重装齐备的雇佣兵
...being deployed into District 9, backed up by significant air support.
在大量的空中支援力量下正在进入第九区
We go shack to shack and get them to sign the form.
我们要挨家挨户叫他们在表格上签名
First one, E-X-triple-seven.
第一家是EX37
We're seeing the convoy stop and the operation is about to begin.
车队停下来了，行动马上就要开始
-Arriving at destination. -Just stay focused.
-到达目地的了 -集中精力
-You ready, Thomas? -Yeah.
-准备好了吗，托马斯？ -是的
-Okay. Yeah, that's it. -Here we go.
-很好，到了 -我们走吧
-Ready, boss? -That's the signal.
-头，准备好了？ -那就是信号
Doors will now open. Please mind the step.
门即将开启 请当心台阶
-You stay behind us. Good luck, boy. -Sure, sure.
-你和我们一组，祝你好运，小伙 -当然，当然
-No, no. Don't split up. -Shit!
不，不，别分开
-Thomas. -We've got the bastard.
-托马斯 -我们打中那混蛋了
Stay, stay, stay. Stay low. Where is he going? What is he--?
别动，别动，别站起来 他这是去哪？那是什么？
Okay, Thomas, move away.
好了，托马斯，走吧
It's clear that security is very high...
很明显此处处于高度戒备状态
...and it's only the beginning of a total clampdown.
这还只是全面驱逐行动的前奏而已
We are here to assist you.
我们在这为您提供服务
Move out. Let's go. Let's go, let's go, let's go!
出去，我们走 走！走！我们走！
Let's go. Move out. Let's go!
我们走，出去，我们走！
This is MNU agents.
我们是MNU探员
-Open the door, please. -Open up, open up. MNU are here.
-请开门 -开门，开门，MNU探员
-MNU. -Always hold your badge up.
-MNU -记得把徽章举着
Hello. Hello. Hello.
你好！你好！你好！
Okay. This is Wikus van de Merwe from MNU.
我是MNU的维库斯·范德默尔
We are here to serve you an eviction notice.
我们是来发放驱逐通知的
You just put your scrawl there.
你只要在这里签字就行了
Fuck off!
滚开
Okay, all right. Thomas, hold it.
好，很好，托马斯，别开枪
We've got the scrawl. As he hit it--
我们已经取得了他的签字 因为它碰到它了
That's what I was saying, it counts as a scrawl.
我的看法是这也算一个
First time you come in, there'll always be a little bit of tension between us--
每次我们进去，彼此之间 总会出现紧张的对立情绪
Hey! Hey, food sack, you can't eat that, man.
嘿，你不能吃那个
The prawn likes to eat the rubber. Like a marshmallow.
大虾喜欢吃橡胶，对他们而言 橡胶就像棉花糖一样好吃
No, no, no! Don't prod him. Don't prod him like that.
别，别！别这样戳他 别这样戳他
Don't prod him.
别这样戳他
Fuck.
笨蛋
You see that. Breaking the rules.
你看到了，他犯规了
No, stay calm.
别，冷静点
Okay, this is gonna be problems. All the prawns are coming out.
好了，问题来了 所有的大虾都出来了
They wanna see what's going on. No, hey. Stop it! Stop it!
他们想弄清是怎么回事 不，嘿，停下！停下！
Horace, bring my goed.
贺拉斯，把我的东西拿过来
See? Everybody's gathering now. Don't shoot.
现在所有的虾都聚集起来了 别开枪
-You're gonna turn it into a war zone. -What is that? Tear gas?
-不然会把这里变成一个战场 -那是什么？催泪弹？
-Is that tear gas? -No, it's cat food.
-是催泪弹么？ -不是，这是猫粮
It's cat food. I just distract them.
这是猫粮，我想引开他们的注意力
Yeah, yeah. He got a bit close, he was prodding a prawn and he--
是的，是的，他离大虾太近了 还戳大虾
He's lost his arm.
结果把手臂给丢了
So we need a team down here straightaway, please, man.
所以我们需要一支队伍 马上，烦请
No, it's not my house. I don't live here.
不，这不是我的房子 我不住在这里
That's a pity, because you know this--
那就很遗憾了 因为你知道…
Hell, this is a nice cat food, you know?
这是一种非常好的猫粮 你知道吧？
But it's not your house, so we'll give it to someone else.
但这既然不是你的房子 我们就要把它给别人了
Yes! It is my house!
是的！这是我的房子！
We need you to sign there. Okay, there it is.
我们要你在这里签名 好了，放在这里
Now you can take that. Okay, all right. Thomas. Thomas, wait. Take it easy.
现在你可以拿走它了 托马斯，托马斯，别紧张，放松点
The creatures became incredibly obsessed with cat food.
那些生物对猫粮有特别的嗜好
Something about that. It was like catnip for cats, only a lot more intense.
正如猫爱猫薄荷一样，不过他们更加钟爱猫粮罢了 （猫薄荷，也叫猫草，猫很喜欢吃）
Get down on the ground or I'll shoot.
趴下，不然就开枪了
Come on. Come on. That's it. Come on.
跟上，跟上 就是那了，跟上
MNU are your friends.
MNU是你们的朋友
Hello? MNU. We are here to serve eviction notices.
你好？MNU，我们正在发放驱逐通知
What is eviction?
什么是驱逐？
Hold it, boys.
停下，伙计
yhat we have stranded on Earth in this colony, is basically the workers.
我们在地球上这个殖民地陷入困境 根本上是因为那些人不会独立思考
Don't think for themselves, take commands, have no initiative.
他们只会唯命是从，他们从不掌握主动权
They've lost all of their leadership through, we presume, illness.
他们丧失了一切领导能力 我们猜想这是疾病所致的
-We are here for you. -Keep your fucking hands up.
-我们是为你们… -你他妈把手举起来
--holding stable in the Nigerian compound area.
我们正在尼日利亚上空执行安全维护
Where there's a slum, there's crime...
有贫民窟的地方就有犯罪
...and District 9 was no exception.
第九区也不例外
The Nigerians had various scams going.
尼日利亚人诡计多端
One of them was the cat-food scam...
其中一种就是猫粮欺诈
...where they sold cat food to the aliens for exorbitant prices.
在那里他们把猫粮价格以 超高的价格出售给外星人
You put the money here first.
先把钱放在这里
You don't get anything until you pay.
不付钱就不能拿到任何东西
What are you trying to do? I'll chop your balls off.
你想干嘛？ 小心我把你的嘴打烂
Not to mention interspecies prostitution.
更别提种间卖淫了
And they also dealt in alien weaponry.
而且他们也买卖外星武器
You have a car hijacking, there's a chop shop there.
他们还劫车，那里就有个赃车店
See that? That's somebody's car in there.
看到了吗？那是别人的车
The Nigerians in District 9 are headed by a man called Obesandjo.
第九区的尼日利亚人的头是一个叫奥卑山卓的人
He's a very powerful underground figure in Johannesburg.
他是约翰内斯堡黑社会组织中一个非常有权势的人
Don't play with these boys. He'll cut you in four pieces.
别和他们打交道，他们会把你剁碎的
-He will put you on each side of-- -Boss. Boss.
-他会把你放在… -头，头
That's the boss there. Okay, no problems. No. Keep walking.
那就是他们的老大，好的，没问题 走过去
Don't look at him. That's gonna cause problems. Trent, don't film here now.
别看他，会惹麻烦的 特伦特，现在别拍
Double up, baby, double up.
叠起来，孩子，叠起来
-All right, next, 766. All right. -Now, this is the one.
-好了，下一个，766 -我们到了
-MNU agents. Open the door, please. -Hey, hey.
-MNU探员，请开门！ -喂，喂
-What? -Jesus.
-什么？ -哇！
-Thomas. Check around the side. -What is it?
-托马斯，查查另一边 -是什么
Check around the side there. That's a--
查查另一边 这是…
Control, it's Wikus van de Merwe. I need a population-control team...
总部，我是维库斯·范德默尔 在四区JV766，我需要一只种群管制队伍
...at JV-766, Zone 4 immediately, please. Check that side, Thomas.
请快点，检查那边，托马斯
-There's 40 to 50 eggs in here. -Is this normal?
-这里有40到50个蛋 -这正常吗？
-This is an amazing find. -They're all gone.
-这真是一个让人惊异的发现 -他们都走开了
I can just show you a little bit how it works.
我向你展示一二它是如何工作的吧
Basically, a cow is hung from the ceiling, you can see.
看这，一头牛被悬挂在天花板上 就如你现在所看到的这样
Very little of it left, of course, because all these pipes supply the nutrition...
它已经所剩无几了 因为所有的这些管道
...to the little prawn eggs.
都在给这些小虾蛋输送营养
-You can do one, if you want. -No, I'm fine.
-如果你想，你可以干掉一个 -不用了，谢谢
You want to see? There you go. Okay. No more nutrition to the guy.
想看不？就这样，好了 这家伙再也没有营养供应了
-And then, finally, we take out that. -Oh, God.
-最后，我们把这个也拔了 -哦，老天
The little guy has gone to a nice little sleep now.
这些小家伙可以好好睡会了
Just pop him out. There we go. And pop him out here.
你把这些东西拔出来 就这样，拔出来
You can take that. Keep it as a souvenir for your first abortion.
你可以留下这个，留作这一次行动的纪念
-You can feel like you did one. -Yes, boss.
-你可以想象你亲手干掉了一个 -是的，头
Where's the team now?
队伍到哪了？
Okay, here he comes, guys.
好了，他们来了，伙计们
This is The Snake.
这是火焰发射器
To go in and abort each egg one at a time would take a very long time.
进去一个蛋一个蛋灭会花上很长一段时间
So this makes a lot of sense.
所以用这玩意才合理
Do you hear that? That's a popping sound that you're hearing.
听到了吗？你们所听到的砰砰的声音
It's almost like a popcorn. What the egg does is, it pops up.
听起来就像是爆米花
The little guy, what's left of him, pops out there.
这些留在那里的小家伙就爆开了
So that's the sound that you are hearing with the popping.
所以大家就听到了砰砰的响声
You don't need that, man. Only sissies wear that. You don't need that.
哥们，不用戴那个，那是姐妹们戴的
-You've been drinking a little bit, eh? -Watch the suit, man.
-喝多了吧？ -小心衣服，伙计们
What are you doing with these television sets here?
你把电视机怎么了？
What's this?
这是什么？
Hey. Smile for the cameras there, eh?
嘿，对着镜头笑一个
-That's a first-day find. -That's a big find.
-这真是首次发现 -是个大发现
You see this? Look at this. Trent. Trent, look at this.
看到没？特伦特，看看这个
There's weapons all over here.
到处都是武器
TK-57572.
TK-57572
Some of the guns are small. But if it shoot you, it make a big mess.
有些枪很小 但一旦被射中，也是威力无穷
MNU is trying to move the aliens for humanitarian reasons...
MNU出于人道的目地要迁走外星人
...but the real focus, just as it has been right from the beginning, is weapons.
但真正的目地，正如一开始所呈现的那样是武器
MNU is the second-Iargest weapons manufacturer in the world.
MNU是世界上第二大武器制造商
We assumed that we'd be able to pick up the alien gun...
我们曾以为我们拿起外星人的枪
...and be able to shoot it. It didn't work like that.
就能够射击，但事实却非如此
As we discovered, their technology is engineered in a biological manner...
因为，研究发现他们的技术实际上结合了生物技术
...and interacts exclusively with their DNA.
要他们的DNA才能启动这些武器
So it just doesn't work with humans. It's as simple as that.
人类就是无法使用，道理就是这样简单
This is basically a guy and there's three humans here.
这画画的是一个大虾和三个人类
Basically, trying to make a warning, you know?
应该是在警告我们，你看
He's saying, "I killed three humans. Watch out for me."
似乎正在宣示：我一人就干掉了三，别惹我
Hey, don't urinate on your own bloody-- Okay. Back up. Back up.
喂，别在自己的地盘上撒尿 退后，退后
Back up, back up, back up. Guys. Thomas.
退后，退后，退后 伙计们，托马斯
Control, this is Wikus requesting First Battalion air support, please.
总部，我是维库斯，请求空中第一营支援
You want to talk to them or you want to talk to me? Yeah, you can talk--
你想和他们谈，还是想和我谈 是的，你可以…
No, not them!
不，不是他们
No.
不
Okay, guys, thanks very much. Yeah, no, he had a spade.
好的，伙计们，太谢谢了 是的，我知道，他有把铲刀
Look! I find some!
看，我找到这个了
I tell you before...
我跟你说过了
...this is human technology...
这是人类的东西
...it is useless.
毫无用处
Only our technology contains the fluid.
只有我们的东西里面才包含着流体
That is not our technology?
这不是我们的东西？
No, it's junk.
不是，这只是垃圾
Keep looking.
继续找
I find something.
我找到了这个东西
Yes. This is what we need.
对了，这才是我们要的
Good, little one.
做得很棒，小家伙
Get down.
趴下
Careful. Wait.
小心点，等会
There.
倒在那边
Why must it take so long?
为什么一定要那么长的时间？
Because it is very difficult...
因为这相当困难...
...so much can go wrong.
很多环节都可能出错
Twenty years of work.
二十年的努力
Our plan is ready now?
我们的计划是不是已经准备好了？
Quiet. Listen.
别出声...听...
They are coming.
...有人过来了
To Control, van de Merwe unit. This is Yankee-Foxtrot-5-3-0.
范德默尔呼叫总部 这是杨基福斯特5-3-0
This is a dangerous area, you know.
这个地段比较危险
You must hide this...
你必须把这个藏起来
...they must not find it.
绝不能让他们发现它
Answer the door and be polite.
开门并礼貌点
No! You take it.
不！你带上它
Okay, now, you see, this is a problem. This is a gang sign. You see this?
你看，这就是问题的关键 这就是帮派的标志，看到没？
So again, looks like we have a-- Thomas, look sharp, eh?
看起来我们找到了… 托马斯，警惕点
Looks like we have more gang members.
看来帮派成员越来越多了
Fundiswa, you just stay back. You stay behind Thomas.
方德斯瓦，你站在后面 站在托马斯后面
This place is swarming with MNU.
这里到处是MNU的人
Open up!
开门
I will be searched.
我肯定会被发现的
I must get back to my son.
我得回到我孩子身边
Don't make them angry. Be polite!
别惹他们生气，礼貌点！
MNU agents. Open the door, please. Hello.
MNU探员，请开门 请开门，喂
Nobody is here.
这里没人
We would like you to please sign-- That's unacceptable.
我们想要你签署… 这是不可接受的
Move out! Move out!
出来！出来！
-That is totally unacceptable! -Get out, you stupid prawn.
-那简直不可接受 -滚出来，你这只蠢虾
-That's bloody rude. Get outside. -Come on. Move!
-那非常不礼貌，出去 -走，出来
-Move! Move! -Get outside.
-走！走！ -出来
We tried to talk nicely with you.
我已经对你相当礼貌了
I tried to talk nicely with him, I did. Get him out to the front there, Thomas.
我对他已经尽量和气了 托马斯，把他押到前面
-Keep moving. -Cheeky bastard.
-继续走 -你这无耻的混蛋
You got something in your house?
你房子里有什么东西？
-All the way, Thomas. -On your knees.
-托马斯，继续… -跪下
-I'm gonna have a look. -Just stay there. Right there.
-我要进去检查一下 -呆在这，就这
Sir, we have to serve you an eviction notice.
先生，我是来给你发放驱逐通知的
Do you understand that?
知道那是什么意思么？
No.
不知道
This is a classic kind of gangster shack. I can tell you...
这是一个典型的帮派窝藏点 非常显然
...we gonna find weapons here.
我们肯定能在这里发现武器
Trent, watch your head. Don't hit the cow's head.
特伦特，小心你的头 别碰着牛肉
Just checking for panels.
检查那些门板
You hear that? Yeah, it's hollow there.
听到没？里面是空的
See? Look at that. Look at that.
看，看那，看那
I haven't seen this type of setup.
我还没看过这样的装置
It's almost like a chemistry type of a set.
它看起来就像一套化学实验装备
There's gonna be something.
这里一定有什么东西
What is this kak?
这是什么玩意？
What is this?
什么玩意？
I don't know. This has got the markings there of--
我不确定，这里有一些标志
So it's definitely alien.
但毫无疑问是外星人的东西
But it's not a weapon.
不过不像是武器
But I don't trust it. You know, I don't trust anything that--
但我信不过这个 不能相信外星人的任何事情
Are you all right?
你没事吧？
-Wikus, are you all right? -Cut it. Turn it off.
-维库斯，你没事吧？ -别录了，别录了
Just switch it off. Turn it off. Turn it off.
关了它，请关了它 关了它
You gonna just-- You gonna cut that part, Trent, out of this?
你会剪掉这段吧?
-Yeah. -Where it sprays me.
-是的 -那段它朝我喷射的
We'll cut that.
我们会把那段剪掉的
We just found a dangerous object here.
我们刚在这里发现了一个危险的东西
It has a fluid in it that I suspect might leak onto people or cause damage.
里面有液体，而且我怀疑沾到人身上会造成伤害
So we just check that in and we take that down nicely to the lab.
所以我们把它装在里面，带回实验室
It's not a weapon, but it's dangerous.
这不是武器，但是很危险
He's got weapons somewhere here.
他在这里一定藏匿有武器
My sense is telling me that. Let's check the other side here.
我的直觉告诉我这点 我们去检查另一边
-Thomas. -Yes, sir?
-托马斯 -是的，先生
-Thomas, keep the gun on him. -I got him.
-托马斯，枪继续对着他 -好的，收到
Keep the gun on him, Thomas. There's weapons here.
枪继续对着他，托马斯 这里有武器
This is Christmas. This is Christmas, my friends.
哦，重大发现！ 重大发现，朋友们
This is the biggest find that I've ever seen.
这是迄今为止最大的发现
Control, come in. This is Wikus van de Merwe...
总部，这是维库斯·范德默尔
...requesting First Reaction Battalion...
请求第一营支援
...at Foxtrot-Yankee-5-3-0.
福斯特杨基530
-I'll send them out to you now, sir. -Stand by, guys.
-现在我马上派他们过去 -准备，伙计们
This I've never seen. Have you seen this? Amazing. Look at this gun.
我从没见过这个，你见过么 太让人惊讶了，看看这枪
-Fuck, man. -What gun is this?
-太屌了 -这是什么枪
-This is absolutely amazing. -Just hold it still.
-这真是太令人惊讶了 -握紧了
-What are you doing? -I wanna show this to Thomas.
-你在干嘛？ -我想把这个给托马斯看
-You said we can't handle them. -I'm just gonna show it.
-你说过我们用不了它 -我只是想展示它
I'm not gonna use it. It doesn't even work with humans.
我不打算用它，人类无法使用
-Thomas, look at this gun. -Yeah. That's a big one, man.
-托马斯，看看这只枪 -是呀，真是个大家伙
That's not mine.
那不是我的
You're a dealer?
你是个军火商？
No.
不是
You hear this? You see what's happening?
你听到了？ 你看到发生的这一切了？
First Battalion, my friend, you know what that means?
第一营，我的朋友 你们知道这意味着什么么？
That means your days of faunting the law are over.
这意味着你逍遥法外的日子结束了
Have a look there. You see that? What's that? That's a hiding for you.
看一看，你看到那了吗？ 那是什么？那是为你准备的
That's a hiding.
那是为你准备的
-Hey. Hey. -Stop that!
-嘿，嘿 -停下
-Stand back! -Hey.
-退后 -嘿
Wikus!
维库斯
Come here.
过来
-Wikus, are you all right? -Come here.
-维库斯！你没事吧？ -过来
Where do you think you're going? Hey. Come on.
你想逃哪去？
-Are you okay? -Fuck off!
-你没事吧？ -滚开！
You don't run away from a chopper. Where are you going?
在刀枪面前，你跑不了 你以为你能跑到哪？
No. No.
不，不
Skeet off, brother. Skeet off.
Koobus to base, come in.
库布斯呼叫基地
I've got two people down.
我们有两个人受伤了
MNU guard, MNU agent.
一名MNU警卫，一名MNU探员
It's Foxtrot-Yankee-5-3-0, copy?
这是福斯特·杨基5-3-0，收到没？
And we need a medevac ASAP.
我们需要医护队，尽快
No, that's fine, Koobus. I don't need the medevac.
不用，没事，库布斯 我并不需要医护人员
-Wikus, you burned your arm. -I'll just treat it here, Koobus.
-维库斯，你的手烧伤了 -我就在这里治疗就行了，库布斯
It's not serious. I'll treat it here.
这不严重，我在这里治疗就行了
I think you must go to a doctor, a hospital.
我认为你得到医院看看医生
-No. -Get it checked out.
-不用 -去医院检查一下
I'll just have it treated by the medics. Just help me-- Help me up quick.
上点药就好了，帮帮我，快扶我起来
Did you see how fast that one was, Trent?
特伦特，你看到大虾跑得有多快了吗？
Yeah, he was fast.
是的，他相当的快
Hell, this guy was fast, I promise you.
见鬼，这家伙跑得相当快 的确相当快
Look, I fix it...
看，我修好它了
...l make it work.
它又能工作了
I told you not to touch that.
我告诉过你别碰它
What is wrong?
出什么事了？
Nothing. Go outside and watch for humans.
没事，你出去放风去
Where is your friend?
你的朋友呢？
He's gone.
他死了
-Are you okay? -Just a bit hot. Are you hot?
-你没事吧？ -没事，就是感觉有点热
-Are you hot, Trent? -Yeah.
-你们觉得热吗？特伦特 -是的
Yeah. If you can't stand the heat, get out of the kitchen.
是的，怕热就别进厨房
That's what I-- That's what I say.
那就是我 那就是我要说的意思
-They are too dangerous. I understand. -You see.
-我知道，他们太危险了 -你看
Another kid. There's just kids everywhere. Kids everywhere.
有一个小孩，到处都能见到小孩
This is what I mean. This is why we get rid of them.
这就是我们要移走他们原因
-The little ones. -That's why we abort.
-这小家伙 -这就是我们为什么要让他们堕胎的原因
-Should I shoot the little bastard? -You can't shoot it now.
-要我一枪把这小混蛋毙了么？ -你不能现在开枪
It's illegal to do that.
这是不合法的
-MNU agent, come out. -Hello.
-MNU探员，出来！ -喂
Hello, little guy. MNU. Here's a sweetie for you, okay.
你好，小家伙 MNU为你带来了糖果
There you go. Eat your sweetie.
去吧，吃你的糖果
Yeah, he's gonna eat his sweetie.
是的，他会吃掉糖果
Works like a charm every time, you know.
这个方法每一次都非常灵验
-Hey. Hey, come on! Hey! -Fuck, man.
-喂，喂，别！喂！ -混蛋
You almost poked my eye out with a fucking lollipop.
你差点用棒棒糖把我的眼睛戳出来了
-I tried to be fucking nice to you! -Hey.
-死小孩，我尽量对你和气了 -喂
Fuck. ls this your fucking little runt here?
妈的，这是你们家的小畜生吗？
Inside, go!
进去，走！
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
对不起，抱歉
You teach him some manners. Thomas, get him out.
好好管教他一下 托马斯，让他出来
Come. Get down! Had enough of you stupid things.
过来，跪下 我早受够了你们这些愚蠢的虾了
What do you want?
你们想怎样？
We're from MNU.
我们是MNU的工作人员
I know.
我知道
We require your scrawl on this eviction notification.
我们要你在这个驱逐通知单上盖个手印
Why am I being evicted?
我为什么要被驱逐？
Yes, it's eviction notice.
是的，这是一个驱逐通知单
Put your scrawl on the bottom. There's your name?
把你的手印按在底下 这是你的名字？
Yes?
是？
Christopher Johnson. Put your name at the bottom.
克里斯多夫·约翰逊 在底部按上你的名字
It says you must give me 24 hours notice.
这里说你们必须24小时前通知我
You're going to another place. A city built for prawns.
你们将到另一个地方 一个专为你们而新建的更好的城市
And we're not even going to charge you. Okay?
而且我们还不向你们收费，明白吗？
This isn't legal.
这不合法
Sign the fucking paper.
签字
No.
不
You don't have a choice. You have to sign the document.
没得选，你必须得签字
This guy's obviously-- He's a little sharper.
这个家伙，很明显他聪明点
You know? So we're gonna have to try something.
所以我们要试试其他办法
Hello.
喂
Okay, seems like we didn't understand each other there properly, eh?
看来我们有些地方没有沟通清楚，嗯
Okay. So you've got a little one, eh? Do you have a license for that?
好了，你有个小家伙，是吧？ 那小孩有办出生证明吗？
Yes.
当然
You see this litter out here? This is dangerous conditions for your child.
你看到周遭的情况了吗？ 这些环境对你孩子的生存是不利的
Article 75 says that because your child is living in dangerous conditions...
75条文件说由于你的小孩生活在 一个危险的环境中
...I'm gonna take him to Child Services. I'll have a chat with your son.
我们会把他带到儿童福利院去 我要跟你的孩子谈谈
You keep away from my child!
离我孩子远点
Don't-- Don't point your fucking tentacles at me.
别用那肮脏的触手指着我
Don't point your fucking tentacles at me.
You want to stay, your boy is coming down with me...
你想留下没问题 你孩子就得和我
...to Child Services. He's gonna spend the rest of his life in a 1-by-1 meter box.
一起去儿童福利院 他的下半辈子就只能在1×1米的箱子里度过了
-Put the gun on him, Thomas. -Hello, little guy.
-托马斯，用枪指着他 -喂，小家伙
It's the sweetie man coming.
好叔叔过来了
Fuck. Look at this, Trent. Fuck.
操，看看这个，特伦特！ 操他妈的！
Thomas. Thomas, keep the gun on him, he's definitely a criminal.
托马斯，拿枪指着他 他是彻头彻尾的罪犯
He's got a whole computer shop here.
这里简直是个电脑商店
He's going nowhere, boss.
他哪也跑不了，头
You know, this is amazing. I mean, this--
我是说，这太让人惊讶了
These are obviously, you can see, stolen computers now...
这里显然是一个，你可以看到 这些失窃的电脑
...that he's decorating his place with.
都被他用作房子的装饰了
Definitely doesn't have a permit for this.
明显他没有申请许可做这事
Where is that fucking little runt?
那该死小毛孩哪去了？
Hello, it's the sweetie man.
喂，这是好叔叔
Here's a sweetie--
Hey, I've got a s--
喂，我有甜甜的
-Hey. Wikus. -Trent, turn it off.
-维库斯! -特伦特,关了它
-Turn off the fucking camera, man. -Wikus, are you okay, boss?
-关掉该死的镜头 -维库斯，你没事吧，头？
-Are you all right? -Fuck off. Fuck off!
-你没事吧？ -滚开，滚开
Shit.
该死
-I said-- -All right, I'll switch it off.
-我说 -好的，我把它关了
-Shall I leave him? -Just leave him here.
-扔下他不管吗？ -不管他了吧
You're lucky.
今天你运气好
We'll come back for you tomorrow, my friend.
明天我会过来找你的
Yeah, I'll see you tomorrow, Christopher Johnson.
明天我会过来见你的，克里斯多夫·约翰逊.
yhen dealing with aliens, try to be polite but firm.
当你和外星人打交道时 态度要和蔼，但立场要坚定
-A smile is cheaper than a bullet. -Are you feeling better?
-并且永远记住微笑比子弹便宜 -感觉好些了吗？
-What? -How are you feeling?
-什么？ -你觉得怎样了？
I'm f-- I'm fine. I'm all right. I'm just-- I'm a bit dizzy.
我很好，我没事 我只是有点头晕
Actually, just pull up there on the side. I just wanna get something to eat here.
在那边停一下吧 我想在那吃点东西
Are you sure you should be having that after your whole puking episode?
你确定你要吃这些吗？ 在你大吐那么长时间后
I actually feel a lot better.
我感觉很好多了
-I think I needed to cleanse. -Boss.
-我想我需要补充能量 -头
Boss.
头
-Boss. Your-- -Wikus, that's-- That's--
-头，你 -维库斯，那是，那是
Black stuff coming out of your nose there.
有黑色的东西从你鼻子里流出来了
MNU总部
Telephone call for Mr. Clark on Line 5.
克拉克先生的电话在5号线
It's a silver cylinder.
那是一个银造的圆筒
I can't find it.
我找不到了
We must find it.
我们必须得找到它
It contains the fluid.
它里面有流体
It's not here.
它不在这里了
It has to be, keep looking.
它应该在这里，再找找
We trade for 1 0,000 cans.
我们要换一万罐
Certain factions of Nigerian gangs want to extract weaponry from District 9...
尼日利亚帮派想把第九区的 外星武器全部购买完
...and have been trying to for years.
他们已经尝试了好多年
Give them one hundred cans.
给他100罐
One hundred.
是的，是的，这次我们全要了
Yes, yes, but we take all of them now.
All right, boys.
好的，伙计们！
Get them the cat food. Hurry up.
给他们猫粮～抓紧了
And they amassed thousands of these weapons...
他们收集了大量的外星武器
...without the ability to use them.
却无法使用它们
Fuck off! Go!
滚开！走！
Hey, friend, not you. You stay here.
嘿，朋友，不是你，你呆在这
What do you want with me?
你想要什么
We just want to talk.
我们只想和你谈谈
Talk about what?
谈什么？
Stupid prawn. They'll believe anything.
蠢虾，他们什么都相信
"Muti" is a South African word.
“穆堤”是个南非词
Today, it's synonymous with witch-doctory and magic.
和魔法或巫术的意思类似
You cut it here.
从这里把它切开
This is the heart.
这是他们的心脏
It cures high blood pressure when you boil it.
煮来吃能够治愈高血压
It cures diabetes, all diseases.
治愈高血糖，糖尿病，能包治百病.
The Nigerians were consuming alien body parts.
尼日利亚人食用外星人
They believed that by doing so, they were ingesting their power...
他们相信这样做可以获取外星人的能力
...to use alien weaponry.
就可以使用外星人的武器
You must eat them. . .
你必须吃掉它们
. . .and their power will live in you.
这样他们的能力才能转移到你的体内
Just give me a fucking chance to go in front of you, man.
让我超个车都不行，妈的
威库斯住处
-Oh, baby, thank God. -Hi, baby.
-哦，宝贝，谢天谢地 -嗨，宝贝
-I need to get to the toilet. -Why?
-我得去趟厕所 -为什么？
-Why are the lights off? -What's the matter?
-为什么灯光都关了？ -怎么了？
-I might have crapped in my pants. -Surprise!
-我都快尿裤子了 -惊喜吗！
-What's this for? -Your promotion.
- 这是干什么？ - 庆祝你的升职呀
Oh, right. Got my promotion.
对，我升职了
-Oh, Dad, how's it going? -Good to see you.
-爸，过得怎样？ -很高兴见到你
Mom, how's it going? That's good. Yeah, what a surprise, man.
妈，过得怎样了？很好 是的，真让人惊喜
-Congrats on the promotion. -Yeah, no, thanks.
-为升职庆祝 -是，不，谢谢
Congratulations, boss. You're gonna be great.
祝贺你，头儿 你会越来越杰出的
-Thanks. -Wikus, what happened?
-谢谢 -维库斯，出什么事了？
Just had a small incident. I'm just gonna go to the toilet...
出了点小意外 我得去趟厕所
...and then I'll talk to the people, okay?
然后再回来跟大伙聊聊，好吗？
-I need to talk to you. Come with me. -Okay, I just gotta--
-我得和你谈谈，和我一起来 -好的，不过我得...
-Guys, can you give us a moment? -Sure, no problem.
-伙计们，能稍等我们一会么？ -当然，没问题
What happened out there?
那边出什么事了？
A small incident.
发生了一些小事情
You know, an unruly prawn and I just had to get him in my grasp.
你知道，那些蛮横的大虾们根本不肯听我的 我不得不亲自抓住他
Listen to me, too many aliens died out there today.
听我说，那里今天死了很多外星人
UIO is all over my backside.
我身后全是UIO的人
Focus. You're not going to fuck this up for me.
听着！你可别给我搞砸了
If you can't do the job, I'll find someone who can.
如果你无法胜任这工作 我就另找他人
-Hi, there. -Hey, it's nice to see you again.
-嗨 -很高兴又见到你们
Now, does this mean he's in charge of this new operation?
现在，这是不是说他要负责这次行动？
-Yes. -That's nice, eh?
-是的 -那太好了
Wikus? Baby, are you okay?
维库斯！宝贝，你没事吧？
Okay, let's cut some cake.
好了，让我们来切蛋糕
Cut some cake.
切蛋糕
-He doesn't look very well. -Are you all right?
-他看起来很不对劲 -你没事吧？
Just calm down, okay?
冷静下来，好吗？
Wikus.
维库斯
Dr. Smith, please come to Room 405. Dr. Smith.
史密斯医生，请到405房间来 史密斯医生
Is it--? ls it badly infected?
是不是感染的特别严重？
There's a lot of suppuration.
大面积化脓了
Also, you should know on my right hand...
还有你应该知道我的右手
...some fingernails were coming loose.
一些手指甲变得很松动
And I had a black fuid coming out of my nose...
还有黑色的液体从我鼻子里流出来
...and sort of a black vomit.
并呕吐过黑色物
What happened to my arm?
我的手怎么了？
-Just breathe deeply. -What happened?
-深呼吸 -出什么事了？
-This is oxygen. -What is this?
-这是氧气 -这是什么？
Just breathe deeply. Calm down.
深呼吸，冷静点
-Stay calm. -Doctor, tell my wife.
-别紧张 -医生，叫我的妻子来
Go tell my wife.
请叫我的妻子来
Attention, all medical staff members, evacuate yard 1 1 immediately.
请注意，所有11区的病人，迅速隔离
All medical staff members, evacuate yard 1 1 immediately.
Who the fuck are you, man?
你他妈是谁？
What the fuck is wrong with you?
你他妈究竟有什么毛病？
Fuck you! Fuck you!
去你妈！去你妈！
Get the fuck off me, you bitch! Fuck!
把那该死的东西拿开 你这婊子，去他妈的
What are you assholes planning on doing?
你们这些混蛋想要做什么？
Stop right there, madam.
停下，夫人
What's going on? What are you doing to him?
怎么回事？ 你们要对他做什么？
-Let go of me! -All right.
-放开我！ -好吧
-Let me through. Let me through! -Good to go. Come on.
让我进去，让我进去
-Wikus. -Madam, get your hands off me.
-维库斯! -夫人，把你的手拿开
Where are you taking him?
你们要把他带到哪去？
We have the infected agent onboard.
我们已经带上了被感染的探员
We're en route to MNU HQ with an ETA of five minutes.
我们正在前往MNU总部途中的直升机上 5分钟内可以到达
Unzip it. Unzip it.
解开，解开
Okay.
好
-You got him? You ready? -Yeah. Got him.
-你抓住他？准备好了？ -抓住了
Decided not to use any anesthetic.
我们决定不用麻醉剂
The reason being, with nitrous, the subject reacts to--
因为不知道会产生什么反应
-Blood pressure is way above normal. -Calm down.
-血压高于正常水平 -安静
The arm is doing some really interesting things.
手臂正在发生一些非常有趣的变化
Aaron, what do you think we've got here?
亚伦，你觉得这是什么东西？
We would have expected it to-- The antibodies to react and maintain.
我们本来预计它的抗体会反应
-Dr. Visser? -Yes?
-维瑟医生？ -什么事？
I think you should see this.
我想你应该看看这个
I found it in his jacket.
我在他的夹克里发现了这个
Do you think this is alien?
这是外星人的吗？
No. No. No.
不，不，不
No, don't.
不，别
Don't. No.
别，别
Sons of bitches leave me-- Fuck.
混蛋，别动我-- 去他妈
暴露16小时后
Where is this?
这是哪？
What?
怎么回事？
What--? What are they doing to these prawns?
怎么回事，他们对这些大虾都做什么了？
Pain threshold, test one, DBX-7.
痛阈测试，第一次，DBX7
Commencing test one, DBX-7.
DBX7，开始测试
Now that's a strong pain reaction.
有很强的疼痛反应
That means the nerves have fused.
说明神经系统已经形成
I mean, it's almost completely integrated.
意思是，几乎融为了一体
Okay, do it.
好吧，开始吧
-B5. -Testing AMR-B5.
-B5 -测试AMR-B5
All right. Okay.
好的
-Clear the range. -Range fire.
-你们走开 -开火
-Now. Quickly. -Quiet, please. We are now recording.
-现在，快 -请安静，我们现在正在录像
Swing it around.
转过来
-What are you doing? -There we go.
-你们要做什么？ -我们去那
What are you doing?
你们要做什么？
-Can you grip that? -What is this?
-你能握住这个吗？ -这是什么？
-Put it through. -Why are you doing that with the gun?
-手扣进去 -你们要我用枪干啥？
-Stand by to fire. -Stand by.
-预备开火 -预备
-You want me to shoot that? -Stand by.
-你们要我射击那个？ -预备
-Stand back. -I cannot use this weapon.
-退后 -我不能使用这武器
And fire.
开火
That's good.
很好
-It worked. That's satisfactory. -AMR-B5 test complete.
-奏效了，很令人满意 -AMR-B5测试完毕
Right. Thanks very much. Load up another target.
好，非常感谢 换上另一个目标
-You got this? -Do you know where my wife is?
-你有这个？ -你知道我的妻子在哪吗？
Do you know if my wife knows where I am? Sir?
你知道我妻子知道我在这里么？先生
Where's my wife?
我妻子在哪？
-Pull. Pull. -I won't do that.
-扣动扳机，扣动扳机 -我不
No, sir, I will not pull it.
不，我不扣
What did you say about your wife?
你刚说老婆怎么来着？
-Fuck your wife. -No, sir. No, please, sir. I will--
-去你老婆 -别，先生，请别这样，我
-I will not pull. -Have to use the prod again.
-我不会开枪的 -得用东西戳下
Fire.
开火
-B7. -AMR-B7.
-B7 -AMR-B7
-I'll pull it. -He says he can pull it.
-我扣 -他说他能扣动它
I can pull the trigger.
我能扣动它
I said I would pull it.
我说我能扣动它
-You rotten pig! -Fire.
-你这只烂猪！ -开火
-B21 . -AMR-B21 .
-B21 -AMR-B21
Move. Hurry up. Move.
过去，快点，过去
We want him in the center, by the chain.
现在，把它弄到铁链中间
-Get this off me. -Come on. Time. Time.
-把这拿开 -继续，时间，时间
Hey, leave that fucking prawn, man. I will shoot a pig.
喂，把该死的大虾弄走 我朝猪开枪就是了
I'll shoot-- Sir. Listen. I'll shoot a pig again for you.
我开枪就是了 先生，听我说，我会为你朝猪肉开枪
I'll pull the trigger, but I'm not shooting that prawn, hear me?
我会开枪的 但我不会朝大虾开枪，听到了没？
-Untie that fucking guy, man. -B21 . The human hand.
-放开那个家伙。 -B21，人手
That's good. It worked.
很好，有用
Just untie that guy. Untie that guy, sir.
只要放开那个家伙。放开那个家伙，先生。
This is-- You can't use the real guy. He didn't do anything.
这，你不能用真枪 他又没犯事
Right. I wanna observe this one. You prod him.
好，我要看看这个 你戳他
-Everybody standing by. -Let him go.
-所有的人闪开 -让他走
Ready to go?
准备好没？
-Don't use a-- Oh, no. -Three, two, one...
-别用那只... -3,2,1...
-Don't, don't, don't. -...go.
-别，别，别 -...开枪
Amazing.
太不可思议了！
AMR-B21 test completed.
AMR-B21测试完毕
All right. I think that's all we need.
好了，我想这就是我们所要的
Gentlemen, you're running out of time.
先生们，我们时间不多了
This is the key stage in the metamorphosis.
这是变形的关键阶段
His DNA is in perfect balance between alien and human.
他的DNA是人类和外星人的完美结合
The problem is, as the infection spreads...
问题是，随着感染的扩大
...the transition becomes permanent and less active.
这个转变会变得永久的 并且越来越没有活力的
He's going to turn into one of them, a prawn?
他将变成外星人的一员 变成一只大虾
What happens to him isn't important.
他变成什么不重要
What's important is that we harvest from him what we can right now.
重要的是我们现在能从他身上获取什么
This body represents hundreds of millions...
这个躯体价值好几百万
...maybe billions of dollars worth of biotechnology.
甚至是价值几十亿美元的生物技术
There are people out there, governments, corporations...
政府、公司所有人都会为
...who would kill for this chance.
这个东西拼个你死我活
-Will he survive the procedure? -No, of course not.
-他能挺得过这些程序吗？ -不，当然不能了
We need everything. Tissue, bone marrow, blood.
我们要他所有的东西 组织，骨髓，血液
The procedure's gonna basically strip him down to nothing.
这个过程会把他拆得一无所有
What about next of kin?
亲属们怎么安置？
Please, help me. Don't let them do it.
求求你帮帮我 别让他们这样做
I'll handle that.
我会处理那些的
Okay. I say, let's go.
好，我说，我们走吧
Good. Thank you.
好，谢谢
I don't understand. None of this makes any sense.
我不明白，一切都说不通
He just hurt his arm, Dad.
爸，他只是手臂受伤了
The doctors are trying, sweetheart.
医生们尽力了，亲爱的
They're doing their best to save him.
尽一切所能在挽救他的生命
We're starting to harvest material from the specimen.
我们已经开始从样本上采集材料了
We'll start with soft tissue first. Cut through the chest cavity.
我们首先从软组织开始 先剖开胸膛
We need to get the heart out quickly.
我们必须尽快取出心脏
Once the septicemia set in, it just spread.
一旦感染病毒了，病毒会飞快传播
-Don't touch me with this gas! -Calm down.
-别用那气管碰我！ -安静
You know Wikus.
你一向知道维库斯
He never was very strong.
他并不是那么强壮
I'll go through the chest, straight into the heart.
我来切开胸膛，取出心脏
-That should quiet him down. -Fuck you!
-那样他就会安静了 -操你妈！
Can I see him?
我能见见他吗？
Not a good idea.
还是不见好
Fuck you. Fuck you!
操你妈！操你妈！
You don't fucking come near me. Don't fucking come near me.
你他妈，别靠近我别靠近我
Fuck you. You big fucking man, huh?
去你妈的，你这该操的人
Hey. Hey. Drop the knife.
喂，喂，扔下刀
Fuck you! Drop that thing or I'll fucking cut his eyes out.
操你妈！放下手上的武器 不然我就把他眼睛戳出来
Okay. All right. Okay.
好的，好吧，好吧
-We're gonna get you, mate. -I'll fucking kill you. I'll kill you.
-我们会抓到你的 -我会杀了你，杀了你
You need to let go of him now.
现在你得放开他了
That's okay, Tania. Everything will be okay.
没事的，蒂尼娅 一切都会好起来的
Smit.
史密斯
When?
什么时候？
Get Koobus.
快叫库布斯
Hey, hey, wait, man.
喂，喂，等会
Wikus van de Merwe, white male, mid-30s...
维库斯·范德默尔，白人 男性，30多岁
...is considered highly dangerous.
高度危险人物
-Hello? -Hi, baby.
-喂？ -嘿，宝贝
-yikus? Is that you? -It's Wikus--
-维库斯，是你吗？ -是的
-Mrs. Smit? Hi. -How dare you phone us.
-史密斯夫人 -你竟敢给我们打电话！
-What are all these people doing? -None of your business.
-你们这些人在我家里干嘛？ -不关你的事
I need to speak to Tania straightaway.
我得和蒂尼娅亲自谈谈
It's my house. This is my phone that you are using.
这是我的房子，你用的是我的电话
-I'm fucking-- What? -It's disgusting.
-我-- 什么？ -真让人作呕
-He tried calling me. -Anton, it's me. It's me. Accept--
-他想给我打电话 -安东，是我，快接电话
Accept the call.
接电话
I've been friends with you for fucking 19 years, man.
我们都有19年的交情了
Fuck off! What are you watching, man? Fuck off!
滚开！你在看什么？ 滚远点
We thought it was for the best because he needed help.
我们都认为这是出于好意 因为他需要帮助
Special medical help. And he wasn't gonna get that as a fugitive.
需要特殊医疗帮助 而如果他继续逃亡的话就无法得到医疗帮助
Move, move, move.
行动，行动，行动
Go, go, go.
走，走，走
He became the most valuable business artifact on Earth.
他已经成为世界上最具商业价值的人了
He was the only human who had ever...
他是唯一一个能够
...successfully been combined with alien genetics and remained alive.
成功和外星基因结合并还活着的人
But his real value was that he could operate alien weaponry.
不过他真正的价值在于他能够使用外星武器
Hello.
你好
Can I get seven schnitzel burgers and a large sauer klopse, please?
我要七个炸肉排汉堡和泡菜
ye interrupt this program to bring you breaking news.
我们中断这个节目并给大家带来一个 惊人的消息
A patient has escaped from the isolation ward and is loose in the city.
有病人从隔离病房逃走 并且在这个城市逃亡
yikus van de Merwe was recently apprehended...
维库斯·范德默尔已经被证实
...after prolonged sexual activity with aliens in District 9.
在第九区和外星人有长期的性行为
Oh, you bliksem.
哦，一派胡言
I have to call my manager.
我得给我的经理打电话
That's totally untrue. You are legally obliged to serve me.
这简直是一派胡言 你本该受命于我的
--which is causing bodily disfigurement.
已经导致他的身体发生变形
Can I buy your burger, please? If I could just--
我能买汉堡么？ 如果我能…
-It's contagious. -Don't listen.
-这具有高度的传染性 -别相信
Police warn people to stay at least 20 meters away.
警方警告民众至少要与这个人保持20米的距离
No, look at this hand. This hand is fine!
别看这个手，这个手没事
If you have any information regarding the whereabouts of van de Merwe...
如果你有此人的任何消息
...please contact us immediately on 0-800-STOP-WIKUS.
请立即通知我们
-You fucking freak! Stop! -Don't go away, after the break....
-你他妈的怪物，停下 -休息后，请别走开…
暴露31小时后
-Hi. This is Tania. -And Wikus.
-你好，这是蒂尼娅 -还有维库斯
ye can't come to the phone right now. Please leave a message. Bye.
我们暂时不能接听电话 请留言
-Bye-bye. -Good things!
拜拜
Control, this is Bird Dog 7. ye're set up at all major exits to the city.
总部，这是鸟犬七号 我们已经在这个城市所有主要出口设立了检查站
There's no sign of Mr. van de Merwe. ye are in total lockdown at this point.
这里还没有维库斯的消息 我们已经完全锁定了这点
The entire world was watching him.
全世界的人都在关注他
He was on every radio station, every image on television.
广播、电视台到处都在报道他
Anything you could find had his face on it.
到处都是他的照片
So he had nowhere else to go.
他已经无路可逃
He ended up hiding in the one place he knew...
他只有一个地方可去
...no one would ever come looking for him.
他知道没人会去那找他
暴露40小时后
I'm not playing here. 6 rand 50 or nothing.
我是来这做生意的 6兰特50，不然就免谈 （兰特，南非货币）
I pay you next week, I promise.
我下周给你，我保证
No money, you get nothing.
没钱别想
Fucking prawn, this isn't a charity.
该死的大虾，这不是慈善
Hello. I'd like to buy some meat, please.
你好，我想买一些肉
Yes, have you got hamburger or, you know, steak roll?
是的，你这里有汉堡 或者牛排卷吗？
Does it look like a hamburger shop?
难道这里看起来像是汉堡店？
-Which one do you want? -Goat, then.
-你要什么肉？ -山羊肉
Come on, come on, come on, man. I don't have all day here.
快点，快点 我可没闲工夫
-Is that cat food there? -Yeah, it is.
-那是猫粮吗？ -是的，那是猫粮
That's cat food, eh? I'll have some of that, guys.
那是猫粮，嗯？ 那来点猫粮
-Is that all? -Yeah.
-就这些吗？ -是的
Fuck, man.
我操
Hello? Hello?
喂？喂？
Ba--
宝…
Baby, is that you? Tania?
宝贝是你吗？蒂尼娅？
Oh, God, please, let it be you.
天呀，希望真的是你
-Yes, it's me. -Baby--
-是的，是我 -宝贝…
I'm so happy you called me, baby.
我真是太高兴了 你给我打电话了，宝贝
-Wikus, listen to me. -Okay.
-维库斯，听我说 -好的
I have something to say to you and it's not gonna be easy.
我有些事情想对你说，但这真难开口
No, okay, look. Listen, baby, before you say anything.
不，不，看...听着，宝贝 在你说任何事情前...
Your father is working against me, baby. He's lying to you.
你父亲不站在我这边 而且他欺骗了你
I did not have sex with one of these. . .
我从来没有跟这些…
...fucking creatures, man.
…这些该死的生物
I would never have any kind of pornographic activity...
我从没和那些外星人发生过性关系
...with a fucking creature. Baby--
…该死的生物有任何形式的性行为，宝贝
But they said that you'd become obsessed with them.
但他们说你变成了他们的一员
I can't do this.
我实在无法接受这点…
Baby, please, don't give up on me, you know?
宝贝，求你了，请别放弃我
Don't give up on me because I can-- I--
千万别放弃我 因为我可以…
I wanna see you again, baby. And I'm gonna fix my arm...
我想再次见到你，宝贝 我的手会好起来的
...and I'm gonna see you again...
…我会再见到你的…
...and I'm gonna kiss you and I'm gonna hold you again.
到时我要亲吻你 要把你搂在怀中
I don't want you to hold me again.
我不想让你抱我了
Baby?
宝贝？宝贝？
Hey, hey. What the--? Hey, hey. Hey, man. Hey.
喂，喂，这是…？ 喂，喂，喂，哥们
Okay.
好吧
--directly to the left of us.
我们正直接追踪至该位置
Roger that. I'll send you a couple choppers back up and--
收到，我会派武装直升机支援你
You!
你！
What do you want?
你想干嘛？
Copy, control. No sign of the target. Moving to Sector 6.
收到，总部，没有目标移动的迹象 前往6区
You have to go.
你得走开
Okay, please, I need your help. Okay?
求你了，我需要你的帮忙 好吗？
Okay. We gonna play hide and seek.
好吗，我们来玩捉迷藏
Yes! Yes!
好的！好的！
You wanna help me hide?
你应该让我藏起来？
No, get back.
不，走开
Show me your favorite hiding place.
告诉我你最喜欢藏在哪？
Please, just go.
走吧，求你了
Leave us alone.
离我们远点
No. Please, you don't-- I need to hide.
不，求求你了，我得藏起来
Okay? They're coming. They wanna kill me. All right?
好不？他们就要过来了 他们会杀了我的，好吧？
I just need to hide here, sir, for five minutes. Okay? I just need to--
我只需要在这里藏起来 就5分钟，好吗？我只需要…
What is this kak? What are you doing here? I remember you.
这是什么玩意？你们在这里干什么？ 我记得你
Nothing. You must hide somewhere else.
什么都没，你一定藏在什么地方
Please, sir, you have to help me. I'm losing blood. They're trying to kill me.
先生，求求你了，我在流血 你得帮帮我，他们会杀了我的
Only one thing that could make that happen.
只有一种东西能让那个发生
Quick, we have to hide him.
快！我们得把他藏起来
Now you, get down there.
你...，下去
Where the fuck I am?
我现在在哪？
Where's the fluid?
流体在哪？
What did you do with it?
你们拿它干什么了？
Please.
求你了
You took it.
你拿走了它
I don't know what you're talking about.
我不知道你在说什么
I know you did.
我知道你拿走了它
I can see what's happening to you.
我可以看出你身上发生的反应
Tell me where it is.
告诉我它在哪里？
Right, right.
好的，好的
Was it a black fuid in a glass container?
它是不是一个装着黑色液体的玻璃瓶？
Yes, that's it. Yes!
是的，就是它，是的！
Right. I confiscated it, and the guys at the lab took it.
我把它没收了 实验室的人拿走了它
It'll be at MNU. MNU has it.
它肯定在MNU MNU的人拿走了这东西
Okay. Okay.
What is this?
那是什么东西？
You ruined everything.
你把一切都毁了
Where is this?
那东西现在在哪？
Is that your shack?
这是你的房子？
This whole thing's under your shack?
这一切的东西都在你房子下面？
For 20 years you've had this fucking thing hidden down here. This is--
20年来，你一直在这里放 你那些重要的东西
This is very illegal.
天呀，这是严重违法的
I mean, this is a fine, you know, if they--
我是说，这简直是个大发现
If they catch you with this.
如果他们把你逮个正着
Fuel goes in here!
能量从这里进去
That's enough! Quiet!
够了！安静！
Then we fly away.
然后我们就可以飞走了
I said quiet! We cannot trust him.
我说安静，我们不能相信他
What is he saying about the fuel? Are you trying to start this thing?
他说的能量是什么？ 你们打算开动飞船吗？
Are you little fuckers trying to start this and get away, eh?
你们这些傻瓜要开动飞船然后飞走？
Never mind.
算了吧
Yeah, you sneaky fucking prawns, eh?
你们这些鬼鬼祟祟的大虾
Too bad. I could've fixed you.
太糟了，我本来可以治好你的
What? What did you say about the fixing?
什么？你说的治好是什么意思？
What, you could fix me?
你说你能治好我是什么意思
Forget it.
算了吧
It doesn't matter, it's too late.
没用了，太晚了
No. No. Listen, listen. Are you saying that you could turn this--
不，听着！听着 你是说你可以
This prawn hand into a human hand? You can make me human again?
把我这只大虾手变成人手？ 你可以让变回人类？
We have medical machines on the mother ship that can fix you. Yes.
我们主船上有医疗设备能够治好你的病
We can use this ship to fly up there.
我们可以开这个小船飞到上面去
That's fantastic. You guys are brilliant, eh?
那太好了！ 你们真是太聪明了！
I always thought the prawns were intelligent.
我一直都认为大虾们很聪明
Let's do it.
那我们开始吧
I don't have fluid.
我没有流体
I could fix you and I could fly away. But I don't have fluid.
我可以治好你，也能飞走 但我没有流体
Right. Right. Okay.
对，对，好吧
All right, I'll tell you what, why don't we go--?
好吧，我来告诉你怎样 我们为什么不...
Let's get some more. Let's go collect some up.
再冒险一次，我们再去收集一些
It took 20 years to collect that amount.
我们花了20年才收集到那一点
Fuck, man. Fuck!
我操！操
Fuck! The only one is the one I confiscated?
操，唯一的那点就是我没收的？
Yes.
是的
It's four stories under ground.
这是地下四层
Why's he keep looking at me like that?
他为什么一直那样看着我？
He likes you.
他喜欢你
We are the same.
我们是同类
Fuck off, man. I'm not the same.
滚，我们不是同类 我们他妈的不是同类
Not the fucking same.
我们不是同类
There is a way out of this.
只剩一个办法能让我们脱离困境
We get the fuid back from MNU.
我们得从MNU手上拿回流体
And what then? Then we both die, eh? Both of us dead.
是呀，然后怎么办？ 然后我们两两都归西？
That's a suicide mission.
这简直是个自杀行动
Can you not fill my head with that sort of nonsense?
你能不能别给我灌输这些愚蠢的主意
The transformation is accelerating.
变形正在加速
You do not have much time.
你的时间已经不多了
Oh, Christ.
哦，上帝
Fuck. Okay.
操，好吧
Fuck. Fuck. Fuck.
操，操，操
-Hello? -Wikus?
-喂？ -维库斯？
-Tania? Baby. -Are you okay?
-蒂尼娅！宝贝 -你没事吧
Oh, God. Thank God.
哦，天呀！谢天谢地
yhere are you?
你在哪？
All those things my father said....
我父亲所说的一切…
I know he was trying to protect me.
我知道他在试图保护我
I just don't know what to believe anymore.
我不知道该相信什么了
Baby, baby, I know, but listen to me. It's all lies.
宝贝，我懂！但是请听我说 这一切都是谎言
I swear to you. Everything he said to you is lies.
我向你发誓 他所说的一切都是谎言
I know.
我知道
What? What?
什么？什么？
I believe you, Wikus. I just want you back.
我相信你，维库斯 我只希望你能回来
I want everything back the way it was.
我想要让一切都回到它原有的状态
That's-- Baby, that's what I want. That's what-- That's great.
这…宝贝，这也是我想要的 这…这太好了
That's great news. I can make it the way it was, if you take me back.
真的太好了，如果你还要我的话 我可以让一切回到过去那样
But how? How can we go back?
但有什么办法？我们怎样才能回到过去？
I have a plan, and I know how to fix it. All right?
我有法子，我知道怎么治好它
I know how to fix myself. And it'll be me...
我知道怎么治好自己的病 然后我又是我了
...and we'll be back together.
我们将会重新在一起
You promise me?
你向我保证
I promise you, baby.
我向你保证，宝贝
Don't give up on me, okay? Because I haven't given up on you, all right?
别放弃我，好吗？ 因为我从不放弃你，好吗？
I won't.
我永远不会放弃你的
I love you.
我爱你
I love you too.
我也爱你
-Tell me you got a fix on him. -D-9.
-告诉我你已经定位到他了 -9区
How many moons does our planet have?
我们的星球有几个月亮呢？
Seven.
7个
This planet only has one.
这个地球只有一个
I can't wait to see our planet.
我等不及见到我们的星球了
It is bigger than this one, isn't it?
它比地球还大，是吗？
Enough.
大多了
We go home now?
我们现在可以回家了？
Not home. No.
还不能回家，不能
This is where we must go.
这个地方我们必须去一趟
See that tent there?
看到那里的帐篷了吗？
That might be ours.
那可能是我们的
I want to go home!
我想回家
We can't go home. Not anymore.
我们回不了了 再也回不去了
Hi. You don't wanna go to the tents. They're not better.
喂，你不会想去那里的 那里不好
They're smaller than the shacks.
那里比这里还小
Actually more like a concentration camp.
实际上，它更像是一个集中营
If I can get you that black fluid, what happens then?
如果我能帮你拿回黑色流体 然后怎样？
We go up to the mother ship.
我们进入母船
And you can start that thing?
然后你可以启动那玩意？
Yes.
是的
Okay. So just to be clear, this is gonna go back--
好的，那么让我们说清楚了 这手将会回到…
This is gonna go back to be human like this.
这手将会回到原来的样子
I can go home.
我可以回家
And then, you can go home. You can take your boy.
你也可以回家，你可以带上你的小孩
You can take all the prawns. If I could get you that fluid, right?
你可以带上所有的大虾 只要我能带来流体的话，对吗？
You said it was a suicide mission.
你说过这是一个自寻死路的任务
Maybe you were right.
你可能是对的？
We have no weapons. They'll shoot us on sight.
我们没有武器 他们一看到我们就会开枪
Look. Look, Christopher.
听着，听着，克里斯多夫
I know where we can get weapons.
我知道到哪里可以搞到武器
Hi, guys. Hello. Hi, hi. Hello.
喂，伙计们，你们好
-I'd like to buy some weapons, please. -No, no, no. Hold it.
-我想买点武器 -不，不，不，等会
How did you do this one, my man?
你究竟是怎么做到的？
It's doggy-style with a demon.
和外星人来后背式
You're one brave white man.
你真是个勇敢的白人
Were you wearing a condom?
有没带安全套
I need to buy weapons, please.
我想要买武器，拜托了
You and I both know that there are illegal weapons inside there.
你和我都知道里面都是些非法武器
I have money and I would like to buy some of those wea--
我带来了钱，我想买那些武器
Okay. Okay. Okay.
好，好，好
-I brought you here to make me money. -Sit. Don't move around.
-我带你来是要让你为我赚钱的 -坐下，别动
You're fucking wasting my time.
你他妈在浪费我的时间
Shut up. Fucking lying bitch.
闭嘴，该死的婊子
Thank-- Thank you, sir, for your time. Thank you very much for seeing me.
谢谢你了，先生，占用你时间了 非常感激你的接见
I would like to buy some weapons.
我想买些武器
AK-47, some grenades, maybe tear-gas canisters.
AK-47，一些手榴弹 催泪瓦斯也行
I see you have limpet mines here, as well.
我知道你还有些武器在那里
And I also see you guys have alien weapons there, which is great.
还看到过你们有外星人的武器 非常强大的武器
I could have one or two of those.
我想买一两件那种武器
I have money, okay?
我带来了钱，好吗？
Now, I'm s--
现在，我…
Sir. Please, sir. Please, sir. Please, sir.
先生，求你了，先生！
I've heard about you.
我听说过你
Where do you have it?
你哪里变形了？
Show me.
给我看看
Oh, shit!
哦，妈呀
Come here. Come.
过来，过来
Shit.
No, no, no. No, please.
别，别…请别这样
Why are you doing that? Why is he--? What is he--? What do you want?
你们这是干嘛？他为什么？ 你要干嘛？
-What do you--? -Shut up.
-你要干…？ -闭嘴
Please.
求你了
Sir, don't.
先生，别
Forget the weapons. Forget the weapons.
当我没说过武器 当我没说过武器
Forget the weapons.
当我没说过
I want the arm. Cut it off.
我要这只手，砍下来
What's he saying? What does he want? What did he say?
他说什么？他要什么？ 他刚说什么了？
What does he want? What does he--?
他要什么？他要什么？
I'll show you. I'm gonna teach you.
我做给你看看 马上就做给你看看了
Hey, hey, hey.
喂，喂，喂
Holy shit.
我靠
You tell them to stand down.
叫他们退下
You tell them to be quiet.
叫他们安静点
You, back off. Put your gun down.
你，退下，放下你的枪
Tell them to put the weapons in the bag, man.
让他们把武器装到口袋里
Fuck. Give me the fucking weapons, man.
妈的，给我该死的武器
Don't you fucking look at me.
别用那样的眼神看我
I said don't fucking look at me.
我说别这样看着我
How did you get that hand?
你究竟是如何长出这只手的？
Fucking hurry up, man.
快点
Look at me when I fucking speak to you.
当我跟你说话时，你他妈看着我
What is your secret?
你的秘密是什么？
What did you do?
你到底做了什么？
Tell me.
告诉我
I want that fucking arm.
我想要他妈的那只手臂
What the fuck did you do?
你到底干了什么
You fucking mizungo, I'm coming for you.
你这个混蛋，我会找你算账的
I'm coming for you. I'm going to get you.
我会去找你的 我会逮着你的
Drop the fucking knife.
放下刀
-Drop your fucking knife! -Easy, easy.
-放下刀 -放松点，放松点
And no live ammo. He's useless to us dead.
用实弹 他死了就对我们就没有一点用处
Would you relax?
你能放松点么？
For fuck's sakes. My men have done this a hundred times before.
为这该死的原因，我手下应付这种事情 至少有100遍了
Maintaining a visual on that location at November-Alpha-1-9-1-1 .
对该目标保持监视
-The unit is closing in now, sir. -It's gonna be quick.
-先生，小组正在靠近目标 -很快就会了结了
It's gonna be clean.
一切都会一干二净
And best of all...
最好…
...it's gonna be quiet.
做得无声无息
Van de Merwe hasn't got a clue what's coming his way.
范德默尔还不知道会发生什么事情
It's empty.
里面没人
Where are they?
他们去哪了？
The target is gone. The place is empty.
目标消失了 此地空无一人
yhat do you mean, "empty"? Where the fuck is he?
你什么意思，没人？ 那他妈到哪去了？
That little shithead has got no idea what's coming his way.
那个小混蛋根本不知道 接下来会发生什么
I'm gonna find him.
我会找到他的
Security breach, Level 2. Please proceed to the nearest exit.
安全警告，2层 请往最近的出口逃散
Do not use--
别用…
There are the guards. At the gate. Watch the guards at the gate, man.
门口那有警卫 小心门口的警卫，伙计
Come on.
走吧
Security breach, Level 2. Please proceed to the nearest exit.
安全警告，2层 请往最近的出口逃散
Move. Get out. Get out!
走，出去，出去
-Don't shoot! -Go.
-别开枪 -走
Going down. Four stories down.
往下走，在下面四楼
This is alien weaponry. Give me a status report.
这是外星武器 给我现状报告
Security breach, Level 4. Bio lab.
安全警告，4层 生化实验室
-It's van de Merwe. He's on Level 4. -Switch to live ammo.
-是范德默尔，他在下面4层 -实弹上膛
-We're taking him out. -Colonel.
-我们要把他搜出来 -上校
We were ordered not to use live ammunition.
我们不允许使用实弹
-They want him alive. -Security breach, Level 4.
-他们想要捉活的 -安全警告，4层
Okay. Stay here until I call you.
好，呆在这里直到我叫你
I understand.
知道了
I need to get the door open.
我得把门打开
Possible alien tissue detected.
发现可疑的外星组织
I said, stay until I call you.
我说过，呆着直到我叫你
Wait for the decontamination process to finish before--
等待净化污染步骤完成…
You trying to get yourself killed?
你想自寻死路么？
Fuck!
该死
I thought you said not to kill them?
我还以为你说别杀他们呢？
He shot at me.
他超我开枪
Open up! Get the fuck out! Don't fucking look at me. Get out!
操！滚出去 别他妈得看着我
Get the fuck out!
出去，都给我滚出去
Okay.
好吧
-Move, move, move. -Get out! Everybody get the fuck out!
-走，走，走 -出去，所有人都给我滚出去
Get out! Go! Move out of here now!
滚开，滚开，现在就滚开
I'll send you home in a fucking jar. Go!
我会用他妈的罐子送你回家的，快走
What is this place?
这是什么地方
Don't worry about that.
别关心那个
What do they do in here?
他们在这做什么？
It's in one of these.
它在这些里面
Check these. Check these boxes.
搜搜那些，搜搜那些盒子
Any kind of a box that looks like it can hold a tube. Just check that.
所有能装管子的盒子都搜查一下
These fuckers.
这些混蛋
Go, go, go.
走，走，走
Clear.
安全
-Security breach.... -I got it! I got it.
-安全警告… -找到了，找到了
Chris, I got it. Let's go. Let's go.
克里斯，我找到了 我们走，我们走
Christopher.
克里斯多夫！
Oh, fuck.
哦，该死
Listen. Listen, I didn't-- I promise you, I didn't know they were doing this.
听我说...我真不知道他们 在这里干什么
Until they brought me here the other day, I swear to you, I did not know...
直到他们上次也把我带进来 我向你发誓，我真的不知道
...they were doing this, but-- Christopher.
他们这样对你们的人，但克里斯多夫
Christopher, listen, look at me. Listen to me.
克里斯多夫，听我说，看着我 听我说
We need to leave now. Okay?
我们现在就得离开，好吗？
The whole of MNU is gonna come down here.
整个MNU的人都要下来了
He's going to destroy us.
他们会杀了我们的
We are big, but quick. We can do this.
我们大，但快，我们能做到
-Okay, we're gonna get out of here. -Target. Fire!
-好了，我们赶紧离开这里 -瞄准，开火
Move, move, move.
走，走，走
Move down the row. Move.
向前移动
-Fuck. -Move close.
-妈的 -向前移动
You fucking bastard.
你这该死的混蛋
-Christopher, what are you doing? -Two o'clock.
-克里斯多夫!你他妈在干啥？ -2点位置
Cover the sides.
包围
The bugs, the bugs, the bugs!
大虫，大虫，大虫
Think of your boy, for fuck's sake.
想想你的孩子
What are you doing? Are you out of your fucking mind?
你究竟在干啥？ 你疯了吗？
Move, move!
走，走
You'll get us killed.
你会让我们都死掉了的
What do we do now?
我们现在该怎么办？
Fuck, yeah, man. Come on.
妈的，是，走
It's a fucking dead end.
这是一个死角
I thought you had a way out?
我还以为你知道出路呢？
I didn't say anything about a way out. I promised you we'd get in. We're in.
我从来没有提到出路 我答应过你我们一定能进来，我们的确进来了
I have an idea.
我有办法了
What? Where are you going?
什么？你要去哪？
Follow me.
跟我来
Follow you?
跟你？
What are you doing?
你在做什么？
Making a bomb!
做炸弹
I've got you, Wikus.
抓到你了，维库斯
Let's go!
我们走
It's a dead end.
这是一个死角
Come on. Get in.
走，进去
Go! Drive!
走，开车
Okay.
好
Okay, hold on.
好，坐稳了
Reports are coming in of an explosion in downtown Johannesburg.
报道来自约翰内斯堡市中心的一个爆炸事件
Well, there was a terrorist attack, but I can assure you we've dealt with it.
那里遭到了一次恐怖袭击 不过我向你们保证，我们正在处理这事
Drop it now. We drop it now. The cunt!
截住他，我们现在截住他 那婊子！
They're really pissed at us now.
他们真的让我们非常恼火
Shit.
妈的
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
我们走，我们走，我们走
Don't drop that fucking thing.
别把那他妈的流体弄丢了
Come on, come on, come on. Move. Get down there.
过来，过来，过来 走，快下去
Go down and initiate the binary commands.
下去输入启动命令
Set it down right now.
赶紧降落
When we get to the mother ship, how long is this gonna take?
我们到达主船时，还要多久才能做好？
To do what?
做什么？
The fixing. To fix me.
治我的病呀
It's going to take a bit longer than I thought.
可能要比我想的费时一些
Okay. All right. That's fine. How long do you need?
好吧，没关系，说吧 要多久？
Three years.
3年
Sorry, wait. Just go slowly with the clicks there.
对不起，等会，慢点说
It sounded like you said "three years." Like human years.
你说的“3年” 听起来像是地球上的3年
Yes. Three years.
是的，3年
What? Three fucking years?
什么？他妈的要三年？
I will fix you...
我会治好你的
...but first I must save my people.
但首先我得拯救我的同伴
The deal was, you go home, I get fixed.
我们的约定是：你能回家 我也能把病治好
I will not let my people be medical experiments!
我不会让我的同胞沦为医学实验品的
I'm a fucking medical experiment. You hear me?
我就是他妈的一个医学实验品 听到我说的了吗？
I'm a fucking medical experiment, man.
我就是他妈的一个医学实验品
I must go home and get help. I must use all the fluid to travel quickly.
我必须回家并搬些救兵过来 我必须用尽所有的流体才能迅速飞回去
I'll just stay here, Christopher. I'll just stay here in this shack.
那我就得呆在这个烂地方了，克里斯多夫 我就得呆在这个鬼地方了
And I'll see you in three years time?
3年后我才能见到你？
I will come back. I promise.
我会回来的，我保证
Hey, Christopher.
嘿，克里斯多夫！
Arriving on the ground. First Reaction Battalion is in pursuit. Over.
抵达地面，第一营士兵已开始行动 完毕
Where the fuck is he?
他妈的去哪了？
Hey.
嘿
You got Wikus down there, my boy?
嘿，你把维库斯藏在下面了？
Father!
爸爸！
No. Your daddy needs to stay there to sort out a few things, all right?
你父亲得呆在这里把一些事情处理好 知道吧？
But we're gonna go and we're come back and fetch him. Okay? All right?
我们得走了，不过我们会回来接他，好吗？
In here?
放进去？
In there.
放进去
It goes in here, eh?
从这里进去，哦？
How the fuck do you open this, prawn?
你们是怎么打开这玩意的，大虾？
Father.
爸爸
Tell me, you fucker. You want me to fucking kill you?
告诉我怎么弄，你这个混蛋 你是不是想让我弄死你？
Hey? Is that what you fucking want? Hey?
嘿？这就是你想要的么，阿？
Hey?
嘿
Okay. Let's see.
好了，让我看看
What?
什么？
What? Okay. There's no buttons.
什么？好，这里没有按钮
-On. -Open it.
-开机 -打开
-Activate. -You have five seconds to tell me.
-激活 -你还有5秒钟告诉我
One prawn, one bullet.
一个大虾，一颗子弹
I can't believe I get paid to do this.
难以置信，我拿钱就是干这事的
I love watching you prawns die.
我爱看着你们大虾死去
What the fuck, man?
我操
Oh, fuck.
哦，操
All right. Okay. Okay.
好了，好，好
Father!
爸爸
Get out! Now!
出去！出去
This is remarkable.
这简直太奇异了
It Iooks Iike something is emerging from the ground.
看起来有什么东西正从地下升起
Something is definitely coming out of the ground.
显然有东西正从地面升起来
All right. All right. Okay. Okay, steady.
好了…稳住
Fuck it.
他妈的
Go sit down. You can't play here now. Your Uncle Wikus is flying.
坐下，我没空搭理你了 维库斯叔叔要飞了
Uncle Wikus is flying now, all right?
维库斯叔叔正在开飞船，对吧？
Fuck. Fuck off.
一边去，一边去
-Hold your track on that target. -Affirmative, colonel.
-武器锁定目标 -当然，上校
Fire when locked.
锁定后就开火
It seems to be drifting towards the center of the territory.
看起来飞船正朝居留区的中央开去
-ye have a Iock. -Fire!
-已经锁定了 -开火
Something has fired upon it. Yes, it's been hit.
有什么向飞船开火了 是的，它打中了飞船
What the fuck is that?
那他妈是什么？
One of the engines is billowing smoke. It's out of control.
有一个引擎已经开始冒烟 飞船开始失去控制了
It's going down, boss. Should I send the boys to fuck him up?
它落下来了，头 要不要我叫些兄弟去干死他们
--now, and-- And it's hit the ground. A massive impact.
现在，飞船已经撞到地上了 重重一撞
And it's come to a standstill.
并完全停了下来
My son!
我的儿子
My son's in there!
我的儿子还在上面
Shut the fuck up! Get this fuck inside. We're moving out. Come, let's go!
闭嘴，把他带进去 我们出发，走，我们走！
-Move him out. That's it. -Move!
-把他带出去 -走
ye're banking around, trying to get a better view...
我们正在向目标靠近 以拍到更清晰的飞船画面
...of the ship, which is wrecked.
飞船已经完全撞毁了
yaiting for some of the smoke to clear.
冒着浓烟正在被清理
Somebody has been pulled out of the vehicle.
有个人被从飞船上带了下来
It Iooks Iike a human being.
看起来像是个人类
ye are getting unconfirmed reports that this might be...
我们得到一个未经证实的消息说他可能是
...yikus van de Merwe, a fugitive that has been on the run...
维库斯·范德默尔，是上周从MNU
...from Multi-National United for the past week.
潜逃出来的犯人
They're loading him into a vehicle now and heading off.
他们把他押上了车，并开走了
Battalion One to Control, confirming prisoners are secured and traveling.
一营呼叫总部，囚犯已经被关牢并正在运送
Expect delivery by 1600 hours.
预计16点移交
What the fuck?
怎么回事？
Back up.
回退
Watch out. Watch out.
当心，当心
We found him, boss.
我们发现他了，头
Bring him to me.
把他给我带过来
Get up. Move! Move!
起来，走，走
-Take cover. Fall back. -We need to regroup.
-找地方掩护，后退 -我们得重新编组
What the fuck?
妈的？
Control, we're taking enemy fire.
总部，我方与敌方交火
We need support. Backup. Backup now!
需要援助，需要援助，快点
Fuck off! No, fuck off, man!
滚开！不，滚开！
Get your hands off me. Fucking get off me!
把手拿开 妈的，离我远点
Get your fucking hands off me! I'll fucking kill you.
把手拿开 我他妈要杀了你
Didn't I tell you. . .
我难道没告诉过你…
. . .that I'm going to get you?
我会找你算账的？
You came that day and left with something that belongs to me.
你那天到这里 然后就拿着本属于我的东西走了
Fuck you.
操你妈
Fuck you. Fuck you! Fuck you!
操你妈！操你妈！操你妈！
Go, go, go.
走，走
Arriving at location. Over.
到达目的地，完毕
Additional troops are moving into place.
越来越多的部队正在驶往这个地区
Go, go, go.
过去，过去
Kill them! Kill all of them!
杀了他们，把他们杀光
Move it.
过去
-Koobus! -Cover the eastern block.
-库布斯 -控制东边
I told you. . .
我告诉过你…
...that the day would come.
这一天会到来的
You've been running around with my prize.
你却带着我的战利品跑了
All I want is to eat that arm and become like you.
我就想吃了你的手 变得和你一样
No, no, no. It won't work.
不！吃我的手不管用...
-Go, go, go. -Move it.
-走，走，走 -过去
Once I have that power. . .
一旦我拥有了那种力量…
. . .no one will stop me.
就没人能够阻止我
It was your turn. . .
风水轮流转
. . .now it's mine.
现在到我了
yith MNU security forces, this armed faction is st--
和MNU安全部队对着干 这些黑帮分子死定了
It won't work.
这样没用的
Let's cut here.
从这里切开吧
Fuck.
操
ye're getting reports of alien devices activating throughout the city.
我们刚得到消息说外星设备已经被启动了
--starting to work again after 20 years--
20年后终于能开始工作了
-Pienaar? -Yeah.
-皮纳尔？ -是
-See that prawn in the Casspir? -Yeah.
-看到那个在车里的大虾了吗？ -是的
He knows what the fuck is up with that ship.
他应该知道上面是怎么回事？
Get the fucker out and get him talking now.
抓他出来，让他开口
-Kronier. -Cover.
-克朗纳 -掩护我
--contractors are closing in on the Nigerian compound, and it--
安全部队正在靠近尼日利亚据点 他们马上…
Over here, cunt. Come outside, you fucking alien. Come here.
来这，笨蛋，出来 你这该死的外星人，过来
What's your plan, huh? What's your plan?
你有什么阴谋？ 你有什么阴谋？
Move, move, move.
过去，过去
How are you doing that?
你们怎么弄到的？
Who's moving that ship?
谁在开那个飞船？
All right. That's very comfort--
好，这相当舒服
Fucking bliksem.
他妈的铁皮
Wait for my command. Make sure you fucking shoot to kill.
等我命令，确保一枪毙命
-Fall back. -What the fuck?
-后退 -这他妈是什么东西
Move it, move it.
走开，走开
Take the right flanks. Take that fucker down.
把那东西干掉
Hold your fire. Hold your fire and keep your positions.
停火！停火！原地别动
It's van de Merwe.
他是范德默尔
Hey, Dickus.
嘿，混蛋
You may have the prawn. Okay? Just let me fucking go.
你留下大虾，好吧？ 就让我离开吧
-Run, Wikus. -You let me go.
-跑呀，维库斯 -你让我走
-Run! -You let me go.
-跑呀 -你让我走
And keep on running, you fucking coward. Run! Run!
继续跑呀 你这个胆小鬼，快跑，快跑
Control. This is Control.
总部，这是总部
Get the air support up and get on his fucking tail now!
请求空中支援 并跟踪他
Copy that. Air support is dispatching now. Over.
收到，空中支援已经部署
It's not gonna work, boss.
没用，头
He's a tough one. He's not gonna talk.
他嘴硬得很 根本不肯说
Then just fucking kill him.
那就直接毙了他
-He's not gonna talk. -Then just fucking kill him.
-他不说 -那就直接毙了他
Fuck.
妈的
-He's a tough one. He's not gonna talk. -Then just fucking kill him.
-他嘴很硬，不肯说 -那就直接毙了他
Hey. Come on.
嘿，过来
I'll get you out of here. I'll get you to the drop ship.
我要带你离开这 我要带你到落下来的船哪去
I can't, it's too far.
我不行了…太远了
It's not too fucking far. Get up.
这他妈一点都不远，快起来
I'm gonna get you there. I'm gonna get you to your boy.
我会带你过去 我要带你回到儿子身边
Come on. Stay behind me. Stay behind me.
来吧，跟在我身后
Retreat! Fall back! Fall back!
撤退，后退，后退
Fall back, fall back, fall back.
后退，后退，后退
Come on, run, run, run. Go.
来吧，跑，跑，跑
Arriving at location now.
现在到达目地的了
We have clearance to engage.
我们马上介入行动
It's coming towards us. Get down, get down.
他超我们过来了 趴下，趴下
Take up positions to the east.
占住东边的位置
Go, guys. Go. Move.
走，伙计们，走
JJ, go for point three. Okay, go, go, go.
JJ，去三点 好了，走，走，走
He's heading for the drop ship. Cut those fuckers off!
他们在朝船过去了 杀了这些混蛋
What the fuck?
操
-Shit. -You fuck.
-该死 -操
Are you hurt?
你受伤了？
No, we can make it. I think the ship's stopping. We can make it. Come on.
不，我们可以做到，我想船正在停下来 我们能做到，快点
Come on. Come on. Come on.
走，走，走
Listen, you go ahead. You can make it.
听着，你往前走 你能够做到的
I'm gonna just hold him off here and I'll join you soon.
我来拖住他们 我待会再和你会合
No, we stick together. I'm not leaving you here.
不，我们要并肩作战 我不会丢下你的
Take your boy and go home. You have to make it.
带着你的孩子回家 你得做到
Don't make me go through this and not make it. Understand?
别让我的辛苦白费了，明白不？
I will come back for you.
我会回来找你的
Go. Go now before I change my mind, man.
赶紧！在我改变主意前
Go!
快走
Three years, I promise.
3年，我答应过你
Fuck! I'm not fucking scared of you.
操，我他妈一点都不怕你们
Big fucking men.
该操的
Come on! Bring what you got!
来呀，朝我开枪呀
Come on!
来呀！
You want me? You want me?
想杀我？想杀我？
Is that all you've got?
你他妈就那点本事吗？
Is that all you've fucking got?
Some sort of quite extraordinary Iight from the mother ship.
从主飞船上发出了一束强烈的光线
I've never seen anything like it. It's a beam of li--
我从来没有见过任何类似的东西 它像一道光束
Select weapons. Okay, fuck. Which one?
选择武器 好，操，哪一种呢？
No, not that one. Go forward. Forward scan. Okay.
不，不是那个，向前 向前扫描，好吧
Fire.
开火
Report. Come in.
报告
Get to the vehicle now. Get going.
把车开过去，快
-Yes, colonel. -Go, go, go.
-是，上校 -快，快，快
Fuck!
操
Fuck. Fuck.
操，操
You wanna fucking play with me, Koobus?
还想和我玩吗？库布斯
You fucker!
你他妈的
He almost got me.
差一点就要被抓到了
Go. Come on.
走，继续
We go home now?
我们现在回家了？
Yes.
是的
暴露74小时后
Unbelievable.
简直难以置信
Now I know why everybody wants a piece of you.
现在我知道为什么人人都想分一杯羹了
I can't wait for those med boys to cut you up.
我都迫不及待想让这些人解剖你了
But you know what? You're not gonna waste any more of my time.
但你知道嘛？ 你再也不会浪费我的一分一秒了
You half-breed piece of shit.
你这个半兽人
I'm gonna just fucking kill you myself.
我要亲手宰了你
Stay back, you fucker.
退后，你他妈的
Stay back.
退后
Stay back!
And people everywhere across Johannesburg...
约翰内斯堡的所有人
...are flooding the streets, are pouring out of their offices.
都冲出了办公室，涌向街头
And all eyes are pointing up towards the sky on this momentous day.
所有的眼睛都在注视着这个重大的场面
It's the first time, ladies and gentlemen, in over two decades...
这是20年来，飞船首次
...that the mother ship has shown any movement...
向大家展示移动的痕迹
...and people are tremendously excited.
人群极度沸腾
The city has come to an absolute standstill.
整座城市都凝固了
And everybody wants to know what's going to happen next.
大家都想知道接下来会发生什么
There's no way of knowing whether Christopher Johnson will return.
究竟克里斯多夫·约翰逊会不会回来 已经无从考证了
We don't know if he was escaping, whether he will effect a rescue plan...
不知道他是不是逃亡了 还是在实施一个营救计划
...and as the so-called free press says...
或者，会不会像媒体所言
...whether or not he'll come back and declare war on us.
会不会回来，向我们宣战
This is the Iast known footage of Wikus van de Merwe.
这是维库斯·范德默尔最后的影像记录
And we can only speculate as to what has happened to him.
他究竟发生了什么 我们只能猜测了
The more zany conspiracy theories state that...
一种阴谋论的理论是这样解释的
...he's been captured by MNU or by another government.
他已经被MNU或他国政府
Or by perhaps some shady government agency...
或者是政府特工逮捕了
...and is actually being held in captivity.
已经被囚禁了起来
If we knew where he was, we would help him.
如果我们知道他在哪里？ 我们会试图帮助他
And that is the most difficult part, just not knowing where he is.
而最大的难点是，我们不知道他身处何方
Wikus, sadly, is gone. . .
维库斯，很不幸的是，已经离开了
...but I'm the one who stays behind with all the questions.
把所有的问题留给了我一个人
I can't give the answers.
而我却无法回答
He died in my mind a long time ago.
在我心里，他早已去了
And that's that.
仅此而已
Wikus van de Merwe is a name that will become very widely known...
维库斯·范德默尔这个名字已经是家喻户晓了
...because of this pivotal role that he played in this whole event.
因为他在整个事件中扮演了关键的角色
He was an honest man and he didn't deserve what happened.
他是一个诚实的人 他不应该承受这一切
I know. I looked into the computer system and I found stuff.
我是说，我进入了一个电脑系统 并发现了一些事实
I mean, the whole data was there, you know?
我的意思是所有的数据都在里面
They didn't even do a good job of hiding it.
他们连藏都没藏好这些数据
You guys haven't seen my wife. Let me show you my wife.
你们还没见过我老婆的照片吧 给你们看看吧
She's my special angel.
她是我的天使
She even looks like a angel with a halo. You want to see?
穿上婚纱，她看起来简直就像是天使 你们想看看吗？
With the white veil over the head, she even looks like an angel.
穿上婚纱，她看起来简直就像是天使
Everyone says his wife's an angel, but this is a real angel that you're seeing.
所有人都说我的老婆是天使 这就是你在镜头下看到的的天使
On the cameras. They won't put that in the video, I don't think.
他们不会把这个也播出去吧 应该不会
I found this at my front door, as though somebody had just left it there.
我在门前发现了这个，一定是某个人留下的
My friends say I should throw it away because it's just a piece of rubbish.
我的朋友们说我应该把这个垃圾扔掉
And it couldn't possibly come from him.
这不可能是他送我的
I know it's true.
但我相信这是真的